<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DBDM on Marianne Elmquist</title>
    <link>marianne-elmquist.com/categories/dbdm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DBDM on Marianne Elmquist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="marianne-elmquist.com/categories/dbdm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IGDILab</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/project/igdilab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/project/igdilab/</guid>
      <description>IGDILab is part of an interdisciplinary, cross-institutional team of researchers developing, validating and applying Individual Growth and Development Indicators (IGDIs) to support data-based decision making to help improve early childhood outcomes. During my time at IGDIlab I primarily worked on the Age 3 IGDI&amp;rsquo;s project, but also briefly helped with the Progress Monitoring IGDI&amp;rsquo;s (PM-IGDIs) project.
Age-3-IGDIs     Project Description: The purpose of the current project was to downward extend IGDIs to three-year olds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting in the Middle: Future Directions for Researchers to Support Educators’ Assessment Literacy and Data-Based Decision Making</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/willetal2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/willetal2019/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   Assessment is prevalent throughout all levels of education in the United States. Even though educators are familiar with the idea of assessing students, familiarity does not necessarily ensure assessment literacy, or data-based decision making (DBDM) knowledge. Assessment literacy and DBDM are critical in education, and early childhood education in particular, to identify and intervene on potential barriers to students&#39; development. Assessment produces data and evidence educators can use to inform intervention and instructional decisions to improve student outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
