<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome! on Marianne Elmquist</title>
    <link>marianne-elmquist.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome! on Marianne Elmquist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="marianne-elmquist.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Child Language Intervention Lab</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/project/child-intervention-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/project/child-intervention-lab/</guid>
      <description>During my Ph.D. I worked on a few projects with Liza Finestack in the Speech-Language-Hearing Science department at the University of Minnesota.
LENA Start™ Smarter Happier Baby Evaluation     Project Description: Along with Scott McConnell, Amanda Kriese, and Erin Lease, we ( Liza and myself) conducted a preliminary evaluation of LENA Start™ being implemented in community settings. We partnered with local Early Childhood Family Education (ECFE) programs to assess the feasibility of implementing LENA Start™ within ECFE classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IGDILab</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/project/igdilab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/project/igdilab/</guid>
      <description>IGDILab is part of an interdisciplinary, cross-institutional team of researchers developing, validating and applying Individual Growth and Development Indicators (IGDIs) to support data-based decision making to help improve early childhood outcomes. During my time at IGDIlab I primarily worked on the Age 3 IGDI&amp;rsquo;s project, but also briefly helped with the Progress Monitoring IGDI&amp;rsquo;s (PM-IGDIs) project.
Age-3-IGDIs     Project Description: The purpose of the current project was to downward extend IGDIs to three-year olds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other blogs I follow</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/blog/blogs-i-follow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/blog/blogs-i-follow/</guid>
      <description> Andrew Zieffler&amp;rsquo;s Blog &amp;ndash; https://www.datadreaming.org/ Craig Van Pay&amp;rsquo;s Blog &amp;ndash; https://cvanpay.github.io/ Britta Bresina &amp;ndash; http://www.brittacookbresina.education/  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telehealth</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/project/telehealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/project/telehealth/</guid>
      <description>Project Description: During the first few years of my PhD program and part of my LEND Fellow pre-doctoral work, I worked with Jessica Simacek, Adel Dimian, and Joe Reichle on some projects evaluating parent-implemented communication interventions for children with complex communication needs (CCN) delivered via telehealth. In addition we collaborated on a number of reviews and tutorials. Some of this work also briefly overlapped with work I conducted with Jennifer McCommas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissertation Work</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/project/dissertation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/project/dissertation/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     Language is an important milestone in early childhood and paves the way for later achievement and outcomes. Early identification and communication-focused interventions can provide additional environmental supports to foster language development for children who face challenges in acquiring language. To accurately identify and predict who may be likely to receive speech/language services, it is crucial to understand the unique contribution and the cumulative effect of factors that best predict speech-language service status and service receipt start time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current trends in telehealth applications to deliver social communication interventions for young children with or at risk for autism spectrum disorder</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/simaceketal2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/simaceketal2020/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   Purpose of Review. Early, intensive, and high-quality interventions can often improve social communication outcomes for children with autism spectrum disorder (ASD). Many children experience barriers to intervention, resulting in significant delays to intervention onset or missed opportunities for intervention altogether. With constant advances in technology, the field is experiencing a rapid increase in investigation of telehealth applications to intervention delivery. This article highlights the current trends in social communication intervention via telehealth used in early intervention practices for children with ASD over the past 5 years, including a brief review of studies (from 2014 to January 2020) and our team’s experiences in this area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parent education to improve early language development: A preliminary evaluation of LENA Start™</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/elmquistetal2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/elmquistetal2020/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   Parents play an important role in creating home language environments that promote language development. A nonequivalent group design was used to evaluate the effectiveness of a community-based implementation of LENA Start™, a parent-training program aimed at increasing the quantity of adult words (AWC) and conversational turns (CT). Parent-child dyads participated in LENA Start™ (n = 39) or a generic parent education program (n = 17). Overall, attendance and engagement in the LENA Start™ program were high: 72% of participants met criteria to graduate from the program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting in the Middle: Future Directions for Researchers to Support Educators’ Assessment Literacy and Data-Based Decision Making</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/willetal2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/willetal2019/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   Assessment is prevalent throughout all levels of education in the United States. Even though educators are familiar with the idea of assessing students, familiarity does not necessarily ensure assessment literacy, or data-based decision making (DBDM) knowledge. Assessment literacy and DBDM are critical in education, and early childhood education in particular, to identify and intervene on potential barriers to students&#39; development. Assessment produces data and evidence educators can use to inform intervention and instructional decisions to improve student outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of aided AAC interventions on speech comprehension of children with neurodevelopmental disabilities: A critically appraised topic</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/elmquistetal2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/elmquistetal2019/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   A critically appraised topic (CAT) is one form of rapid review that can be particularly useful for informing practice. The purpose of this CAT was twofold: to determine (a) the impact of aided augmentative and alternative communication interventions on speech and graphic symbol comprehension in children, aged birth-18 years with neurodevelopmental disabilities and (b) whether there are any potential learner characteristics that serve as moderators or mediators regarding intervention outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintenance and generalization in functional behavior assessment/behavior intervention plan literature.</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/penningtonetal2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/penningtonetal2019/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   School practitioners increasingly use functional behavior assessments to design behavior intervention plans when students engage in challenging behavior that is not improved by classroom management or standard interventions. Behavior intervention plans should aim to produce behavior change that maintains across time and generalizes to relevant contexts. In applied terms, maintenance occurs when a behavior continues to occur after the intervention is fully or partially withdrawn; generalization occurs when a learner engages in a trained behavior in an untrained context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typography Styles &amp; Element Examples</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 12:27:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/elements/</guid>
      <description>Font Sizes   A A A A A A A A   6rem
(96px) 5rem
(80px) 3rem
(48px) 2.25rem
(36px) 1.5rem
(24px) 1.25rem
(20px) 1rem
(16px) .875rem
(14px)     Type Samples Head&amp;shy;line Sub&amp;shy;head&amp;shy;line Level 1 Heading One page to rule them all...well, not really. This page displays sample typography and page elements to illustrate their style. Things like headings and paragraphs showing the beautiful type scale, form elements, tabular data, and image layouts just to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toward an ecobehavioral model of early language development</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/fordetal2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/fordetal2020/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   Language development is an important milestone in early childhood that has implications for laterachievement. Although a variety of contemporary models have been offered to describe the process oflanguage acquisition, ecobehavioral models provide descriptive and actionable information on both thecausal mechanisms of behavior change and development, as well as variables of influence (e.g., settings,environment, policies). Grounded within sociolinguistic theory and empirical literature, we propose anddescribe an ecobehavioral model of language development that assumes language is learned through theopportunities afforded by caregiver–child interactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promoting conditional use of communication skills for learners with complex communication needs: A tutorial</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/simaceketal2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/simaceketal2018/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   Purpose: Conditional use of communication skills refers to the ability of a learner to appropriately generalize and discriminate when, where, and how to communicate based on constant variation and shifts in environmental cues. Method: We describe discrimination and generalization challenges encountered by learners with complex communication needs and ways in which these challenges are fostered through traditional communication intervention programming. We address arrangements in instruction that maximize the probability of learners acquiring the conditional use of new vocabulary and the modest instructional technology implemented when planning for generalization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching communicative responses with a speech-generating device via telehealth coaching</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/dimianetal2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/dimianetal2018/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   Caregivers need support with teaching augmentative and alternative communication (AAC). The purpose of this study was to coach caregivers via telehealth (i.e., live video conferencing with Google Hangout) to implement communication assessments, functional communication training (FCT), and/or navigation training to address either idiosyncratic or problem behavior exhibited by two young boys with developmental delay (age 5.5 years) and autism (age 7 years) who were non-verbal. An adapted multiple probe design and a multiple probe design across three contexts (play, break from demands, help) were used to evaluate acquisition of communicative requests using high tech aided AAC on a speech-generating device (SGD; a Tobii Dynavox T10 device).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coaching parents to assess and treat self‐injurious behaviour via telehealth</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/bensonetal2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/bensonetal2018/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   The application of telehealth technology to conduct functional analysis (FA) and functional communication training (FCT) is emerging for children with developmental disabilities and behaviour support needs. The current study was designed to extend FA + FCT for self-injurious behaviour by using telehealth in home with parents as interventionists receiving real-time remote coaching. Two families with school-aged boys with developmental disabilities associated with intellectual disability participated, one with cerebral palsy and the other with autism spectrum disorder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributors</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/contributors/</guid>
      <description>Thank you to all the folks who have contributed both technical and creative skills to this project:
   Desirée De Leon 🦒 (designed 5 of the custom color themes, made illustrations for the workshop, and provided general aesthetic feedback along the way)
   Garrick Aden-Buie 🧙‍♀️ (debugged headroom.js and lent his panelset.js code to the theme)
   Allison Horst 🐕 (awesome illustrations of campfires, seedlings, and evergreens, as well as my R Markdown hedgehog mascot 🦔)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
