<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LENA on Marianne Elmquist</title>
    <link>marianne-elmquist.com/categories/lena/</link>
    <description>Recent content in LENA on Marianne Elmquist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="marianne-elmquist.com/categories/lena/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Child Language Intervention Lab</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/project/child-intervention-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/project/child-intervention-lab/</guid>
      <description>During my Ph.D. I worked on a few projects with Liza Finestack in the Speech-Language-Hearing Science department at the University of Minnesota.
LENA Start™ Smarter Happier Baby Evaluation     Project Description: Along with Scott McConnell, Amanda Kriese, and Erin Lease, we ( Liza and myself) conducted a preliminary evaluation of LENA Start™ being implemented in community settings. We partnered with local Early Childhood Family Education (ECFE) programs to assess the feasibility of implementing LENA Start™ within ECFE classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parent education to improve early language development: A preliminary evaluation of LENA Start™</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/elmquistetal2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/elmquistetal2020/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   Parents play an important role in creating home language environments that promote language development. A nonequivalent group design was used to evaluate the effectiveness of a community-based implementation of LENA Start™, a parent-training program aimed at increasing the quantity of adult words (AWC) and conversational turns (CT). Parent-child dyads participated in LENA Start™ (n = 39) or a generic parent education program (n = 17). Overall, attendance and engagement in the LENA Start™ program were high: 72% of participants met criteria to graduate from the program.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
