<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Projects on Marianne Elmquist</title>
    <link>marianne-elmquist.com/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in My Projects on Marianne Elmquist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="marianne-elmquist.com/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Child Language Intervention Lab</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/project/child-intervention-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/project/child-intervention-lab/</guid>
      <description>During my Ph.D. I worked on a few projects with Liza Finestack in the Speech-Language-Hearing Science department at the University of Minnesota.
LENA Start™ Smarter Happier Baby Evaluation     Project Description: Along with Scott McConnell, Amanda Kriese, and Erin Lease, we ( Liza and myself) conducted a preliminary evaluation of LENA Start™ being implemented in community settings. We partnered with local Early Childhood Family Education (ECFE) programs to assess the feasibility of implementing LENA Start™ within ECFE classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IGDILab</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/project/igdilab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/project/igdilab/</guid>
      <description>IGDILab is part of an interdisciplinary, cross-institutional team of researchers developing, validating and applying Individual Growth and Development Indicators (IGDIs) to support data-based decision making to help improve early childhood outcomes. During my time at IGDIlab I primarily worked on the Age 3 IGDI&amp;rsquo;s project, but also briefly helped with the Progress Monitoring IGDI&amp;rsquo;s (PM-IGDIs) project.
Age-3-IGDIs     Project Description: The purpose of the current project was to downward extend IGDIs to three-year olds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telehealth</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/project/telehealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/project/telehealth/</guid>
      <description>Project Description: During the first few years of my PhD program and part of my LEND Fellow pre-doctoral work, I worked with Jessica Simacek, Adel Dimian, and Joe Reichle on some projects evaluating parent-implemented communication interventions for children with complex communication needs (CCN) delivered via telehealth. In addition we collaborated on a number of reviews and tutorials. Some of this work also briefly overlapped with work I conducted with Jennifer McCommas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissertation Work</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/project/dissertation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/project/dissertation/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     Language is an important milestone in early childhood and paves the way for later achievement and outcomes. Early identification and communication-focused interventions can provide additional environmental supports to foster language development for children who face challenges in acquiring language. To accurately identify and predict who may be likely to receive speech/language services, it is crucial to understand the unique contribution and the cumulative effect of factors that best predict speech-language service status and service receipt start time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
