<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>telehealth on Marianne Elmquist</title>
    <link>marianne-elmquist.com/categories/telehealth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in telehealth on Marianne Elmquist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="marianne-elmquist.com/categories/telehealth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Telehealth</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/project/telehealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/project/telehealth/</guid>
      <description>Project Description: During the first few years of my PhD program and part of my LEND Fellow pre-doctoral work, I worked with Jessica Simacek, Adel Dimian, and Joe Reichle on some projects evaluating parent-implemented communication interventions for children with complex communication needs (CCN) delivered via telehealth. In addition we collaborated on a number of reviews and tutorials. Some of this work also briefly overlapped with work I conducted with Jennifer McCommas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current trends in telehealth applications to deliver social communication interventions for young children with or at risk for autism spectrum disorder</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/simaceketal2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/simaceketal2020/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   Purpose of Review. Early, intensive, and high-quality interventions can often improve social communication outcomes for children with autism spectrum disorder (ASD). Many children experience barriers to intervention, resulting in significant delays to intervention onset or missed opportunities for intervention altogether. With constant advances in technology, the field is experiencing a rapid increase in investigation of telehealth applications to intervention delivery. This article highlights the current trends in social communication intervention via telehealth used in early intervention practices for children with ASD over the past 5 years, including a brief review of studies (from 2014 to January 2020) and our team’s experiences in this area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching communicative responses with a speech-generating device via telehealth coaching</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/dimianetal2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/dimianetal2018/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   Caregivers need support with teaching augmentative and alternative communication (AAC). The purpose of this study was to coach caregivers via telehealth (i.e., live video conferencing with Google Hangout) to implement communication assessments, functional communication training (FCT), and/or navigation training to address either idiosyncratic or problem behavior exhibited by two young boys with developmental delay (age 5.5 years) and autism (age 7 years) who were non-verbal. An adapted multiple probe design and a multiple probe design across three contexts (play, break from demands, help) were used to evaluate acquisition of communicative requests using high tech aided AAC on a speech-generating device (SGD; a Tobii Dynavox T10 device).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coaching parents to assess and treat self‐injurious behaviour via telehealth</title>
      <link>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/bensonetal2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>marianne-elmquist.com/publications/bensonetal2018/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   The application of telehealth technology to conduct functional analysis (FA) and functional communication training (FCT) is emerging for children with developmental disabilities and behaviour support needs. The current study was designed to extend FA + FCT for self-injurious behaviour by using telehealth in home with parents as interventionists receiving real-time remote coaching. Two families with school-aged boys with developmental disabilities associated with intellectual disability participated, one with cerebral palsy and the other with autism spectrum disorder.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
